[Music]
[音乐]
hello everyone welcome back in today's lecture we will
大家好，欢迎回到今天的讲座，我们将
see the osi security architecture as usual we will start the session with
像往常一样看到 osi 安全架构，我们将开始课程，
the outcomes upon the completion of the session the learner will be able to
课程结束后，学习者将能够获得
outcome number one we will know the difference between
第一名的结果，我们将知道
threat and attack outcome number two we will understand the osi security
威胁和威胁之间的区别 攻击结果二 我们将了解 osi 安全
architecture and outcome number three we will know
架构和结果三 我们将
about security attacks security services and security
了解安全攻击安全服务和安全
mechanisms before we step into what is threat and
机制在我们讨论什么是威胁和
attack let's see an analogy just contemplate you want to protect
攻击之前让我们看一个类比，只是考虑您想要保护
your home and your belongings in your home from
您的家和您的财物 在您的家中免受
unauthorized access obviously you will prefer a strong
未经授权的访问显然您会更喜欢坚固的
lock and if you prefer a lock that is made of plastic
锁，如果您更喜欢由塑料制成
of course it can protect to some extent and not to the extent of security that
的锁，它当然可以在一定程度上保护而不是
can be offered by a metal lock i hope you can understand this say you
金属锁可以提供的安全程度我希望你 可以理解这说您
are preferring a plastic lock instead of a metal lock
更喜欢塑料锁而不是金属锁，
you know what will be the impact of a plastic lock in place of a metal lock
您知道塑料锁会产生什么影响用 ock 代替金属锁，
but still plastic locks can offer some degree of security
但塑料锁仍然可以提供一定程度的安全性
maybe kids can't break it easily so you understood that there is a threat with
也许孩子们不能轻易打破它，所以您了解塑料锁存在威胁，
the plastic lock because it can be easily broken so you
因为它很容易被打破，所以
have decided to replace it with the metal lock and you know
您决定更换它 使用金属锁，你知道
metal lock it will be hard to break when compared to the plastic
金属锁与塑料锁相比很难打破
lock and after replacing the plastic lock with the metal lock
，在用金属锁替换塑料锁后，
do you think there is no security vulnerability or security issues
你认为没有安全漏洞或安全问题
let's assume somehow you secure your home with a metal lock
让我们假设你以某种方式保护你的家 一把金属锁，
but still your home is vulnerable to threats you know why
但你的家仍然容易受到威胁你知道为什么
attackers may attack the metal lock also and if you feel that metal lock is fully
攻击者也可能攻击金属锁，如果你觉得金属锁得到了充分
protected and nobody can break the metal lock but
保护，没有人可以打破金属锁，但
still there are vulnerabilities i'll tell you where just assume you have
仍然存在漏洞，我会告诉你刚才在哪里 假设您
a poor quality window and so trespassers can
的窗户质量很差，因此侵入者可以
enter home through your window and they may not prefer the regular way by
通过您的窗户进入家中，他们可能不喜欢打破金属锁的常规方式
breaking the metal lock let's also assume your home is having a
让我们也假设您的家
poor roofing system so that attackers can enter your home
屋顶系统很差，因此攻击者可以进入您的家，
and take your belongings through your poor roofing system by breaking your
并通过破坏您的屋顶系统将您的财物通过您的屋顶系统，
roofing system so your home is vulnerable to attack
因此如果您的窗户质量差，那么您的家仍然容易受到攻击，
still if you have a poor quality window then
那么
obviously still your home is not safe your home is
显然您的家仍然不安全
still vulnerable to threats if someone is successful in breaking
如果有人成功破坏了
your security system and enter your home and steal your
您的安全系统并进入您的家中并偷走了您的
belongings this is what we call as attack in this example there always
财物，您的家仍然容易受到威胁，这就是我们在这个例子中所说的攻击，总是
exist a potential for violation of security in
存在以不良屋顶系统形式违反安全的可能性
the form of poor roofing system or poor quality
或质量差的
window and if there is a potential violation of
窗户，如果
security in your home then it is a threat so i hope you can
您家中存在潜在的安全隐患，那么这是一种威胁，所以我希望您能
understand this say if you have a potential violation of
理解这一点，如果您家中存在潜在的
security in your home then it is a threat to your home and if
安全隐患，那么这对您的家庭构成威胁，如果
someone enters your home and steals your belongings
有人进入您的家并偷走您的财物
it is an attack the intention of this lecture is knowing about threats and
这是一次攻击本讲座的目的是了解威胁和
attacks let's dive into the definition of
攻击让我们深入了解defi
threats and attacks what is a threat it is a potential for
威胁和攻击的概念什么是威胁 它是潜在
violation of security which exists when there is a
的安全违规行为 当存在可能滋生安全并造成伤害的
circumstance capability action or event that could breed
环境能力行动或事件
security and cause harm that is a threat is a possible danger
时存在的潜在威胁 威胁是可能利用漏洞的潜在危险
that might exploit a vulnerability just understand you might have protected your
您可能已经
home with a secure system or a locking system
使用安全系统或锁定系统保护了您的家，
but still your home is vulnerable to threats you know why
但您的家仍然容易受到威胁，您知道原因，
because there exists a poor quality window and
因为存在质量差的窗户，并且
attacks can happen based on the poor quality window so obviously there is a
可能会根据质量差的窗户发生攻击，因此显然存在
possible danger that might exploit a vulnerability and
可能的危险 可能会利用一个漏洞，
where is that vulnerability it is in the form of poor quality window
该漏洞在哪里，它以低质量窗口的形式出现，
so before attack can happen there should be a threat and this threat
所以在攻击发生之前应该存在威胁，这种
is a possible danger that might exploit a vulnerability so
威胁是可能利用漏洞的潜在危险，所以
this is about a threat now let's see what is an attack an
这是关于威胁的，现在让我们看看是什么
attack is an assault on system security that derives from an intelligent threat
是攻击 攻击是对系统安全性的攻击，源自智能威胁，智能威胁
that is an intelligent act that is a deliberate
是一种智能行为 是一种蓄意的
attempt especially in the sense of a method or
尝试，尤其是在
technique to evade security services and violate the security policy of a
逃避安全服务和违反系统安全政策的方法或技术的意义上
system say if someone has entered your home
说，如果有人进入您的家
and stolen your belongings it is an attack actually
并偷走了您的财物，这实际上是一种攻击，
you are affected because of that the attack will be a deliberate one and
因为攻击会影响您是故意的，
that's why the statement is mentioned as it is a
这就是为什么提到该声明，因为它是
deliberate attempt and how this attempt is made it is made
故意的尝试，以及如何进行这种尝试，它
in the form of a method or a technique and normally attack will be an
是以方法或技术的形式进行的，通常攻击将是一种
intelligent threat because attackers are intelligent guys i
智能威胁，因为攻击者是聪明人
am not praising the attackers but please make a note of it
我是 不赞扬攻击者，但请记下它，
because they are able to find out some flaws in the security system
因为他们能够发现安全系统中的一些缺陷，
and they are making use of that vulnerability and gaining access
并且他们正在利用该漏洞并获得访问权限，
so obviously attackers are knowledgeable guys so we should not underestimate
所以显然攻击者是知识渊博的人，所以我们不应该低估
attackers whenever you create any secured system
攻击者每当你创建 任何安全系统
always think in the perspective of attackers and
总是站在攻击者的角度思考，并
think is there any possibility for the attackers to get into your system
认为攻击者有可能获得 进入您的系统
and take away your data or your belongings i hope now you are clear with
并带走您的数据或您的财物 我希望您现在清楚
what is a threat and what is an attack let's now dive into the topic of the day
什么是威胁和什么是攻击现在让我们深入探讨当今的主题
the osa security architecture the osc security architecture deals with
osa 安全架构 osc 安全架构处理
three things number one the security attack number
第一件事 安全攻击
two the security mechanism and number three the security services
第二个安全机制和第三个安全服务
so we will talk about this one by one elaborately in the coming lectures
所以我们将在接下来的讲座中详细讨论这个
but i will give you an introduction of all the topics now
但我会给你介绍所有主题现在
say someone has stolen your information it is an attack
说有人窃取了你的信息这是攻击
someone is sniffing your conversation it is an attack someone is able to gain
有人在窃听您的对话 这是一种攻击 有人能够
access to your secure system it is an attack say someone defacing a server
访问您的安全系统 这是一种攻击 说有人破坏了服务器
from functioning properly it is an attack so firstly we will focus
的正常运行这是一种攻击 所以首先我们将
on the security attack this attack means it is the action that
关注安全攻击这种攻击意味着它是
compromises the security so whenever any action is carried out
危害安全性的操作，因此无论何时执行任何操作
and because of that your security system is compromised then it is called as an
并且因此您的安全系统受到危害，它都被称为
attack then what is security mechanism it is to
攻击那么什么是安全机制 检测安全
detect prevent or recover from a security
机制或从安全
attack the security mechanism must be proactive as well as reactive
攻击中恢复 安全机制必须是主动的和被动的
suppose if there is an attack that has happened so the security mechanism
假设如果发生了攻击，那么安全机制
should come into action and recover the system to its original state
应该开始行动并将系统恢复到 原
the security system not only react to the attack but should also prevent
状态 安全系统不仅对攻击做出反应，而且还应该在攻击
attack before it happens and not only this it should also detect
发生之前阻止攻击，不仅如此，它还应该检测
any attack if it has happened so this is about the security mechanism
任何攻击，如果它发生了，所以这是关于安全机制
and coming to the last one the security services so security
，最后是安全服务，所以 安全
services enhances the security counter security attacks and provide the
服务增强了安全反安全攻击并提供
service see there are various services that we
服务 看到
are expecting from a security system don't worry about this we are going to
我们期望从安全系统获得的各种服务不要担心这个我们将
talk about that elaborately in the coming lectures
在接下来的讲座中详细讨论，
but in this lecture i will be providing a basic understanding about attacks
但在本次讲座中，我将 提供对攻击机制和服务的基本了解
mechanisms and services basically the attacks are of two types
基本上攻击有两种类型
number one is the passive attack and number two
第一是 t 被动攻击，第二个
is the active attack we will see about the attacks in the next lecture with
是主动攻击，我们将在下一节课中看到关于攻击的
examples before we conclude let's also see what
例子，在我们总结之前让我们
about security mechanisms and services coming to security services
看看安全机制和服务如何进入安全服务
there are lot of security services that we are expecting from a secure system
有很多安全服务，我们期望从一个 安全
the authentication service the access control
系统 身份验证服务 访问
the data confidentiality the data integrity
控制 数据机密性 数据完整性
and non-repudiation i can very well understand
和不可否认性 我可以很好地理解
these terms are new to you don't worry about these terms or
这些术语对您来说是新的 不要担心这些术语或
any new terms you hear in this lecture we are going to see all the
您在本讲座中听到的任何新术语我们将看到
terminologies in this lecture series so that's it
本讲座系列中的所有术语，这就是
about the security services and coming to the security mechanisms we
关于安全服务和安全机制的内容 我们
have a lot of mechanisms to detect prevent or recover from a security
有很多机制来检测防止或从安全
attack the mechanisms include encipherment
攻击中恢复这些机制包括加密
digital signatures access control data integrity
数字签名访问控制数据完整性
authentication exchange traffic padding routing control and
认证交换流量填充路由 控制和
notarization we are done with the three components of
公证我们完成了o的三个组件
the osa security architecture the security attacks the security
sa 安全架构 安全攻击 安全
mechanisms and the security services we have just seen what are the three
机制和安全服务我们刚刚看到了什么是
components in the coming lectures anyway we are going to deal about this
接下来的讲座中的三个组成部分 无论如何我们将详细讨论这个问题
elaborately and that's it guys i hope now you
我希望现在你们
understood the difference between threat and attack
了解威胁和攻击之间的区别
you understood the osa security architecture and we also have come to
您了解了 osa 安全架构，我们也
know about the security attacks security services and security
了解了安全攻击安全服务和安全
mechanisms i hope you guys enjoyed today's lecture
机制，希望大家喜欢今天的讲座
and thank you for watching
，感谢大家的收看